+514-577-3103

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | NETWORK SECURITY

https://iamanshulgit.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/anshul-anshul-928bib37/

#### **PROFILE**

Quality-driven Computer engineer driven to improve business and customer operations effectively overseeing all types and sizes of complex projects. Strategic planner bringing four years of experience in directing technological improvements, project plans and documentation.

Looking for internship in a result-oriented company that seeks a smart working and career conscious person who acquired skills and education will be utilized towards continuous improvement and advancement.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Efficient data management
- Design and Development
- Cybersecurity analysis

- Application/Software Development
- Configuration Management
- Conflict Resolution

### **EXPERIENCES**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

(09/2017 - 12/2018)

### Royal Lightening Industry- Delhi, India

- Devised automation, backup and recovery protocols for MySQL databases to preserve and safeguard over essential amount of data.
- Programmed applications and tools using Java and MySQL with goals for code abstraction, stability and reuse.
- Modified existing software systems to enhance performance and add new features such as Email Notification and Autogenerated pay slips.
- Gathered, organized and analyzed data for program development.

## **COMPUTER FACULTY**

(01/2014 - 08/2017)

## SIOC Education and Charitable Trust- Delhi, India

- Instructed students on use of technology tools and equipment as well as methods for accessing information.
- Developed written instructions and handouts to supplement course lectures.
- Evaluated and adjusted course curriculum based on student overall performance and assessments.
- Planned and prepared lectures and lessons covering areas of information technology such as C++ and Java with MySQL.
- Monitored student progress through frequent assessment of various computer tasks.

# TECHNICAL

# SKILLS

**Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing**: Log Analysis, Network Security, Network Traffic Monitoring and Analysis, SQL Injection, XSS, ARP-Scan, Metasploit, MFSVenom, Nessus, Wireshark, Snort, Maltego, Burp Suit and Acunetix

Programming Technologies: Java, C++, C#, HTML/CSS, MySQL, Swing

**Networking**: Cisco Firewall/Switch/Router, DNS, DHCP, SAN, iptables, NAT rules, Cisco ASA, ACL, Active Directory, NTFS sharing, FSRM, DFS, GPO, Failover Cluster, NBL

Operating System: Linux (CentOS/Ubuntu/Kali) and Windows (Server 2012R2/2016)

Virtualization: VMware, VirtualBox and HyperV

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Integration Network Project**

I designed a network with layer2 and layer 3 wiring, switching and routing using TPLink and UNIFI devices. A small organization network where two Domain Controller (Windows) is in one network accompanied with one webserver (CentOS). Numerous of services are installed according to the guidelines such as DNS, DHCP, GPOs, DFS, FSRM, Roaming Profile, Printers, Quotas and Filters. For security and blocking unwanted access of services, ACLs and firewall configurations are followed. To run a service when logon, I used logon scripts.

#### **Location Alarm**

I developed an android application where a person can search an address as well as mark it simultaneously. When the person reaches near to that location (around 1km) then alarm tone is enabled to notify about it. In the background, it is updating the distance between current location and destination. Java, XML

#### **SQL Truncation**

An OWASP vulnerability in which a user can get access to the pre-existing user with only username. Vulnerability found in WordPress.com which was later patched. It was performed on local server.

## **E-commerce Web Application**

A website with login registration page for personal database where they can list different products by name, category. Fill the items in cart, change/remove the quantities of articles with checkout functionality. After checkout, email sent to their mail and register the articles in the database. Java, MySQL.

#### **Password Saver**

I developed an application where a person can save all the username and password of different accounts with a functionality of two-factory authentication in which a mail is sent for verification at the time of login. Java, MySQL.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Programming and Network Security - Post graduation Diploma

2019 - 2021

Institut supérieur d'informatique - Montreal, Quebec

# **Computer Science Engineering - Bachelor**

2009 - 2013

Maharishi Dayanand University - India

## OTHER

- Lucideus Certified Ethical Hacker Grade 1
- Lucideus Certified Ethical Hacker Grade 2
  Micro Certification on SQL Injection at Cybrary

# LANGUAGES

**ACHIEVEMENT** 

- English (Professional Proficiency)
- French (Elementary Proficiency)
- Hindi (Native Proficiency)

Reference upon Request